Russell E. Harmon

Contact Information Rochester Institute of Technology PO Box 92423 Rochester, NY 14692

(585) 210-3330 http://rus.har.mn russ@eatnumber1.com

SUMMARY

I love to tinker. I enjoy spending my time working on personal projects. Some of the notable projects I have worked on include the Linux kernel and the Gentoo Linux distribution. I have become very good at picking up new ideas quickly, and expanding what I already know with a direction and my own research.

EDUCATION

Rochester Institute of Technology - Rochester, NY

September 2006 - Present

- Major: B.S./M.S. Computer Science
- M.S. GPA: 3.0
- Minor: Music, Concentration: Computer Engineering
- Expected graduation: February 2013

EXPERIENCE

Google - Mountain View, CA Chrome OS Kernel Engineering Intern

6/5/2012 - Present http://google.com/

Currently working on the Kernel team for the Chromebook. My work centers around the creation of a unit test which analyzes the kernel-to-kernel latency of input events, and the associated frameworks to make this test possible. This work involves adding trace events into the Linux kernel, X input drivers, and the Chromium browser; then building tools to analyze traces generated by these events.

Microsoft - Boston, MA Software Development Engineering Intern

6/6/2011 - 8/26/2011 http://micorosft.com/

Worked on the "Sustained Engineering" team on the Application Virtualization product. The sustained engineering team maintains the released version of App-V. Written in C++, I worked on an as of yet unreleased feature for the App-V and Office products.

Apple Inc - Cupertino, CA Engineering Intern

6/1/2010 - 11/16/2010 http://apple.com/

Worked on the "Platform Kernel" team in the Core OS department at Apple. The majority of my work entailed work on libC, and on XNU (the Mac OS X kernel). My two major projects were (a) migrating code out of the kernel into userspace to take advantage of ASLR and (b) creation of an automated testing suite to test Mac OS X's power management on Intel processors. The ASLR work involved a great deal of collaboration between several different teams within Apple.

SafeNet Inc - Belcamp, MD Engineering Intern

June 2008 - June 2010 http://www.safenet-inc.com/

Worked on the SafeNet Management Console (SMC) on a team of 7. SMC is a web application built on Java, JBoss, Hibernate and JSF which manages high speed network encryption devices that SafeNet manufactures, including top-secret devices. Responsibilities included (a) creating requirements documents, (b) implementing requirements (IPv6, file synchronization), (c) testing and (d) fixing defects. Some of the specific tasks that were assigned while working there included transparent file synchronization between machines, implementing IPv6 support and implementing support for multiple SMC servers managing the same device (distributed devices).

CERTIFICATIONS

TECHNICAL SKILLS & Fluent Languages (a) C (b) Java (c) ZSH (d) C++ (e) Javascript (f) Python Operating Systems (a) Linux [programming & administration] (b) Mac OS X (c) Windows Server Administration (a) LDAP (b) Kerberos (c) BIND (d) DHCPD (e) Radvd (f) Apache Networking (a) Cisco Academy, with honors (terms 1 and 2) (b) IPv6 (c) DNS (d) DHCP (e) IPSec Tools (a) Make (b) Autotools (c) CMake (d) LLVM (e) Regex (f) LATEX

Special ACCOMPLISHMENTS Joined CSH (Computer Science House). While there, I was elected by my peers first as a network administrator, then as the director of all the network administrators. http://www.csh.rit.edu/ At age 8, built my first computer. At age 10, worked my first job at City Island Computer Services. At age 12, attended my first programming class at Lehman College.